The British Empire branded them as outlaws. The oppressed called them heroes.
Ned Kelly is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Gregor Jordan.
After getting threatened by Kelly's friends and family, Constable Fitzpatrick
places the blame on Ned Kelly and exaggerates what happened.
With the biggest ever award available, Kelly and his gang set into the
wild, to remain hidden from everyone who seeks them.
Even if it means having his family arrested, the members of the Kelly
Gang stay hidden and plan a way to get their names cleared.
Ned Kelly, played by Heath Ledger.
Joseph Byrne, played by Orlando Bloom.
Superintendent Francis Hare, played by Geoffrey Rush.
Julia Cook, played by Naomi Watts.
Aaron Sherritt, played by Joel Edgerton.
Dan Kelly, played by Laurence Kinlan.
Ned Kelly is a 2003 bushranger film based on Robert
Drewe's 1991 novel Our Sunshine.
Directed by Gregor Jordan, the film's adapted screenplay
was written by John Michael McDonagh.
The film dramatises the life of Ned Kelly, a legendary bushranger and
outlaw who was active mostly in the colony of Victoria.
In the film, Kelly, his brother Dan, and two other associates—Steve Hart and Joe
Byrne—form a gang of bushrangers in response to acts of police brutality.
Heath Ledger stars in the title role, with Orlando
Bloom, Naomi Watts and Geoffrey Rush.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $6 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of australia, resistance,
folk hero, lawlessness, fugitive.
The tone is emotional.